<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jetty on jk jensen</title>
    <link>https://jkjensen.me/tags/jetty/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jetty on jk jensen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 09:25:52 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jkjensen.me/tags/jetty/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data Risk and Data Reward</title>
      <link>https://jkjensen.me/posts/2022-10-05-data-risk-reward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 09:25:52 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jkjensen.me/posts/2022-10-05-data-risk-reward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Generative AI tools are making headlines. Society is beginning to see the vast potential of data and the risk that accompanies it. This is healthy! We should dive headfirst into this path while working to measure progress both objectively and subjectively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Excuse me for a few minutes while I dump a (mostly) train-of-thought polemic here about data utility and measuring societal progress.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-is-used-today-for-important-things&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;data is used today for important things.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some would suggest otherwise but for the most important organizations on earth, data is not a competitive advantage. It is &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; competitive advantage (sorry &lt;a href=&#34;https://benn.substack.com/p/do-data-driven-companies-win&#34;&gt;@bennstancil&lt;/a&gt;). Collecting, operating on, and making inference from data yields an understanding of people more broad-reaching and comprehensive than our brains are accustomed to. I’m going to coin a term because this is the internet and you can do things like that – I call it &lt;strong&gt;The Hark Paradox.&lt;/strong&gt; The paradox is that people positively assert the impossibility of internet companies listening to their everyday conversations and producing advertising insights from them. To me it is clear evidence of the mismatch between expectation and reality. Evidence to the contrary pointing to battery life or microphone sensitivity or recency bias don’t convince people that they’re not being spied on. We can’t explain it, so we attribute it to magic. Speaking of which…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
