<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Goals on jk jensen</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/goals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Goals on jk jensen</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 09:25:52 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/goals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>interviewing my parents</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-10-31-interviewing-my-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 09:25:52 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-10-31-interviewing-my-parents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every day in the month of May I conducted recorded interviews with my parents. We faced a host of technical difficulties and sometimes I lost several minutes&amp;rsquo; worth of precious recording because of them. Here are some interesting lessons I learned.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;av-problems-abounded&#34;&gt;a/v problems abounded&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have a new appreciation for people who live code or game on streaming platforms. Getting the audio and video right is tricky.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge I faced trying to record interviews was making both the interviewer &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the interviewee audible through the process. I was using my Macbook Pro to do this, and MacOS doesn&amp;rsquo;t support threading streams together, so I had to install and configure a &lt;a href=&#34;https://rogueamoeba.com/freebies/soundflower/&#34;&gt;kernel extension&lt;/a&gt;{:target=&amp;ldquo;blank&amp;rdquo;} that would handle it for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what i learned running 4 miles a day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-05-07-running-4-miles-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 14:25:52 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2020-05-07-running-4-miles-a-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I ran 4 miles a day, 6 days a week. It was greuling some days, but I did a hard thing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-joy-in-hard-things&#34;&gt;finding joy in hard things&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Each aspect of my life has been challenged before, from faith to health to morality to aspiration. After every setback it is easy to see, in retrospect, the difficulty I was faced with. I recognize that my life has been for the most part one full of privilege – I am grateful and undeserving of the life given me. My experience, though, has taught me that &lt;em&gt;it is good to be faced with moderate opposition&lt;/em&gt;. Even my closest friends and I hold opposing views.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
